827 Purple Martin Court Warrington, PA 18976

Tom Kaufmann

tommy-k@comcast.net https://linkedin.com/in/tommykaufmann

Summary:

Resourceful, determined leader offering almost a decade of experience in engineering, managing & delivering projects implemented across multidisciplinary engineering teams. Capability of analyzing and managing critical business requirements while mentoring teams to strive for engineering excellence in execution. Consistently driving solutions that enhance operational efficiency for large enterprises.

Employment:

Sr. Engineering Manager Engineering Manager

Cigna

May 2020 – Present March 2019 – May 2020

Leader of Middleware's Integration Services & API Management team. Responsible for the Engineering, Delivery, and Operations related to critical middleware infrastructure.

- Driving improvements in communications between engineering and operations teams by personally leading meetings and negotiating process improvements around engagement, automation & ongoing support
- Product owner of an Enterprise-wide business initiative to preserve enterprise support & double our current infrastructure for Layer7 API Gateway to increase resiliency and bandwidth
- Led an R&D business initiative onboarding a new API Management solution enhancing Cigna's service offerings
- Providing quarterly updates to business leads on current licensing allocations to stay within contract compliance and to assist with contract renegotiation
- Created and maintained disaster recovery plan and business continuity plans which later enabled two hour turnaround in data recovery
- Responsible for \$2M+ budget to recruit and retain top talent in order to modernize our technological footprint
- Providing quarterly updates to business leads on current licensing allocations to stay within contractual compliance and to assist with contract renegotiations of approximately \$5M AUM

Sr. Infrastructure Engineer

Cigna

March 2017 - March 2019

Technical Lead in Operations for Service-Oriented Architecture (SOA) infrastructure team in order to provide stability for critical middleware infrastructure across multiple LOBs.

- Provided KPIs for Developers & QA Engineers to identify issues reducing future impacts to deliverables in Production
- Developed enterprise SOPs among multiple environments across multiple technologies to improve operational efficiency of our application teams
- Responsible for the administration of 500+ middleware-tiered infrastructure appliances and application servers
- Defined and implemented new standards for infrastructure processes and environments aligned to industry best practices that improved our security, reliability and resiliency
- Provided project oversight of each year's key initiatives for multiple middleware-tiers and software projects
- Constructed new Splunk & Dynatrace dashboards enhancing our organization's monitoring capabilities, reducing our missed SLA's by 40%
- Improved efficiency of daily workflows by leading engineers to focus on automation, reducing operations ticket volume by over 55%

Infrastructure Engineer (TECDP)

Cigna

January 2014 - March 2017

Engineer on the Application Performance Management Team for an International Fortune 100 Healthcare Company.

- Deployed CA APM Introscope Agents for Performance Monitoring across multiple applications, totaling over 2,000 JVMs
- Defined monitoring & metrics standards for JBoss EAP, WAS and IIS agents implemented across the enterprise
- Developed & implemented standard, or application-specific, monitoring profiles and support the diagnosis of application problems by utilizing systems management tools
- Advised application teams on defining KPIs and created multiple dashboards for a high level view of overall performance

- Helped to create multiple self-service forms/scripts to help automate monitoring within CA APM Introscope for our application and infrastructure teams
- Technical Lead for onboarding new hires to Systems Management tool and providing necessary training
- Product Owner for Aternity Infrastructure, responsible for defining standards & reviewing new product releases
- Experience in Windows, Linux, and UNIX environments

Education:

Bachelors of Science, Information Sciences & Technology, May 2011 Temple University, Philadelphia, PA

References & other work experience available upon request